# KARTHIKEYA BHAT

+91 8867010724 • bhatk.442@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/karthikeya-bhat-b5a6971b6 • github.com/KarthikeyaBhat

#### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic and problem-solving oriented, I am a quick learner with a relentless desire for growth. I proactively take on challenges while maintaining flexibility to adapt and adjust to maintain efficiency. By using strategy, delegation, and adaptability techniques, I have worked well in managing time across various projects leading to completion.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Tech., Computer Science and Engineering**

Graduating May 2024

PES University, Bangalore, KA, India

8.95 CGPA

Department of Computer Science and Engineering

Relevant coursework: Data Structures, Algorithms, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Database Management Systems, Cloud Computing, Machine learning, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Web Development

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

**Programming:** C, C++, Python, Java, JavaScript, Solidity

Frameworks: React.js, Node.js, Flask

Database: MySQL, MongoDB

**Tools:** Git, GitHub

**Course work:** Data structures and its applications, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Object Oriented Analysis and Design, Operating Systems, Computer Networks, Database Management Systems, Cloud Computing, Machine learning, Blockchain

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Pronisi LLC, Bangalore, KA, India: Software Engineering Intern

June 2023 – Aug 2023

- Played a pivotal role in developing the Minimum Viable Product (MVP) by actively contributing to the productionready codebase.
- Demonstrated proficiency in Python, JavaScript, AWS, and MongoDB through valuable contributions.

#### Interra, Bangalore, KA, India: Software Engineering Intern

Aug 2022 - Nov 2022

- Developed the front end for a social networking platform from scratch (Rect.js, Node.js, Tailwind CSS)
- Conducted Knowledge Transfer sessions to train new interns.

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

#### NFT enhanced Blockchain-based social network application

May 2023 - Dec 2023

Collaborated in a team of four to design and implement a social media website using blockchain.

- As part of the capstone project, we developed a social media application using blockchain. Here users own their data and can sell/buy their posts in NFT marketplace as NFTs.
- Technologies used: Solidity, HardHat, ERC721, NodeJS, ReactJS, IPFS, Polygon.

# **Cross-platform Multiplayer Quiz Application**

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023

Led team of four to design and develop a cross-platform user-friendly multiplayer quiz app.

Used MVC design pattern and employed Java's Spring boot framework.

#### Grocery delivery web application

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

Collaborated in a team of four and implemented a grocery delivery web application.

• Created a RESTful web application with features such as authentication, data management etc. Employed Firebase for the backend and React.js for the front end.

#### **Employee management system**

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

Collaborated in a team to develop a multifunctional dashboard for employee management

• Built a DBMS software with a web interface. Supports CRUD operations which can be performed directly from the website. Employed Python's Flask framework and used SQL for database operations.

# **ACTIVITIES**

# Apple Developers' Group - PES University

Nov 2021 - Present

Tech team member

- Created a website for the Apple Developers' Group at PES University, employing technologies such as ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, and Tailwind CSS.
- Used by students to register for events and to learn about club activities.

# **AWARDS**

• Awarded M.R.D scholarship for being in the top 20% of the department 2nd, 5th and 6th semesters.